# Vimukthi Madushan

**Gender:** Male | **Phone number:** (+358) 415765303 (Mobile) | **Email address:** madushan.gangoda94@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/vimukthi-madushan

### ABOUT ME

#### Who I am:

a software engineer who is presently residing in Finland with a Finnish residence permit. having 4+ years of practical experience in full-stack development, as well as extensive knowledge and skills in designing, creating, and implementing cloud software solutions. The cross-functional team is led to the greatest result by a good team player. a dedicated learner with a solid grounding in the principles of software engineering. a person who enjoys technology and is motivated to understand new developments in the field.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

07/2021 - 07/08/2023 Colombo, Sri Lanka

#### LEAD DEVELOPER ELEGANT MEDIA PVT LTD

<u>Elegant Media</u> is a leading Web and Mobile application development company in Melbourne, Australia. My responsibility was to develop scalable and reliable backend team and develop Web Applications with the relevant team.

## As a **Lead Developer**, I was responsible for

- Cording, proper technology selection, and usage.
- Architecture designing and developing various system features in the web and cloud-based
- applications Including both front-end and back-end development.
- Create standard operating procedures for repetitive work and distribute them to team members.
- Create and maintain libraries / Conduct training sessions / R&D and feasibility assessments.

### As a **Team Lead**, I was responsible for

- Set clear goals and delegate tasks within the team.
- Ensuring the quality of deliverables / Resolving conflicts and issues in the team and clients.
- Effective communication across the team and manage resources within the team.

#### **Technology Stack**

• Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, React, Redux, AWS, PHP, Javascript, Laravel, MySQL, MongoDB, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

02/2021 - 06/2021 Colombo, Sri Lanka

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER INCUBATE LABS**

- Implemented Node.js and Express.js backend, delivering a robust and responsive server-side architecture.
- Collaborated with a cross-functional team to develop and launch <u>Cloudofgoods</u>.
- Develop jobeka website with Spring Boot framework
- Utilized Git for version control and participated in agile development practices to ensure project milestones were met on time.

## **Technology Stack**

 Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, React, Redux, Javascript, AWS, Microservice Architecture, Java, Spring Boot, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

12/2018 - 02/2021 Colombo, Sri Lanka

## **SOFTWARE ENGINEER** WEBLOOK INTERNATIONAL

- Developed a hotel booking engine from Express framework as a product of Weblook with multiple payment gateways and Beds24 channel manager integration.
- Developed a food ordering system and mobile API for a Canadian client with Express framework.
- Maintained an e-commerce cart web system developed from Laravel.
- Researched the implementation of OctoberCMS (a Laravel-based CMS) for medium-level projects.

### **Technology Stack**

Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, React, Redux, Javascript, PHP, Laravel, OctoberCMS, VueJs, MySQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

#### WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER PIXEL ART CO PVT LTD

- Rebuild the official website with an admin access panel to maintain the website.
- Develop a taxi management system for book and rent out taxis online.

#### **Technical Stack**

PHP, Laravel, Codelgniter, WordPress, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

08/05/2015 - 23/10/2018 Sri Lanka

## **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE** University Of Ruhuna

Address Wellamadama, Matara, 81000, Sri Lanka | Website https://www.ruh.ac.lk/ |

Field of study Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics

03/2018 - 09/2018 Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

### CISCO NETWORKING CENTER - CCNA ROUTING AND SWITCHING University of Moratuwa

Field of study Introduction to Networks, Connecting Networks, Scaling Networks, Routing and Switching Essentials

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

### My Digital Skills

Node.js, Express, TypeScript, React js, Redux, AWS, Docker, Javascript, Vue.js, PHP, JAVA, Laravel, Spring Boot, OctoberCMS, Git, Jira, Livewire, JQuery, HTML, CSS

## **PROJECTS**

**Child Protection Blutooth Module.** Developed a Bluetooth module and mobile application from Java language to detect when the Bluetooth module is approximately 100 meters away from the mobile phone. If the Bluetooth module is too far away from the mobile phone, it will ring.

We presented this device to the ENVENTION AND INNOVATION EXHIBITION-2015 organized by the faculty of science at the University of Ruhuna under the electronic category.

#### **Tech Stack**

Java, C++, Android

**Minor Offense Management System.** Completed a web-based project related to the Police Department of Sri Lanka as my final year project at the University.

### **Tech Stack**

• PHP, Laravel, Javascript, jQuery, CSS

## **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

## **Sports**

- Vice-Captain of Badminton team Faculty of Science (2016).
- Captain of Badminton team Faculty of Science (2017).
- Member of University Road Race Team.
- Member of University Badminton pool.